If you want me to teach you French, you must teach me muay, Monsieur Mek.
إذا كنت تريد مني أن أعلمك الفرنسية، يجب عليك أن تعلمني الملاكمة، يا سيد ميك.
I will make sure my lessons match your kindness.
سأتأكد من أن دروسى تتناسب مع لطفك.
PREVIOUSLY
سابقا
Let me show you how the French do it.
دعني أريك كيف يفعل الفرنسيون ذلك.
Rati!
أسعار!
I suddenly felt like I was burning inside despite being in the water.
فجأة شعرت وكأنني أحترق من الداخل على الرغم من وجودي في الماء.
He is engaged.
إنه مخطوب.
Would you still say that you were not disgusted by me?
هل ستظل تقول أنك لم تشعر بالاشمئزاز مني؟
Is that you, my lord?
هل هذا أنت يا سيدي؟
THEE
أنت
Smells lovely.
رائحتها جميلة.
Do you like it?
هل أحببت ذلك؟
I must be dreaming.
لابد أنني أحلم.
It's nice.
إنه لطيف.
Is it?
هل هو كذلك؟
I'll stop by every morning.
سأتوقف كل صباح.
Would you like that?
هل يعجبك ذلك؟
Thee?
أنت؟
I brought you this bunga rumpai.
لقد أحضرت لك هذا البونجا رومباي.
The scent of rose petals and cloves helps you feel relaxed.
رائحة بتلات الورد والقرنفل تساعدك على الشعور بالاسترخاء.
Put it next to your pillow
ضعها بجانب وسادتك
to remind you of the person who gave it to you.
لتذكيرك بالشخص الذي أعطاك إياه.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
How did you get into my room?
كيف دخلت إلى غرفتي؟
It's time to get up. You have a lesson to teach today.
حان وقت الاستيقاظ. لديك درسٌ لتعلّمه اليوم.
Or would you like me to…?
أم تريدني أن...؟
I'm up!
انا مستيقظ!
Coffee, sir.
قهوة يا سيدي.
Thanks, Jam.
شكرا لك، جيم.
Of course.
بالطبع.
Thee.
أنت.
Don't look at me like that.
لا تنظر إلي بهذه الطريقة.
Like what?
مثل ماذا؟
Like…
يحب…
Like you're really happy.
كأنك سعيد حقًا.
- Unlike the way you look at me, my lord. - Jam. Don't you have work to do?
- على عكس نظرتك إليّ يا سيدي. - جام. أليس لديك عمل؟
I do. But I want to be here.
نعم، ولكنني أريد أن أكون هنا.
Get to work.
اذهب إلى العمل.
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي.
- Jam. - Yes?
- مربى. - نعم؟
Work.
عمل.
Yes.
نعم.
I'll leave your food here.
سأترك طعامك هنا.
I didn't mean to make you feel uncomfortable by staring,
لم أقصد أن أجعلك تشعر بعدم الارتياح من خلال التحديق،
but I couldn't help myself.
ولكنني لم أستطع مساعدة نفسي.
You have to.
عليك أن.
How could I when we…?
كيف يمكنني ذلك عندما...؟
Thee!
اليك!
You are so unbending.
أنت غير قابل للانحناء.
Each day, they seem more and more than just friends.
كل يوم يبدو أنهم أكثر من مجرد أصدقاء.
Soon enough, people will talk.
قريبا سوف يتحدث الناس.
Those two?
هؤلاء الاثنان؟
Surely you're overthinking it.
من المؤكد أنك تفكر في الأمر أكثر من اللازم.
It's you who needs to think a little!
أنت من يحتاج إلى التفكير قليلاً!
Don't you see the way the count looks at Mr. Rati like…?
ألا ترى الطريقة التي ينظر بها الكونت إلى السيد راتي مثل ...؟
Stop it! You're giving me goosebumps.
توقف! أنت تجعلني أشعر بالقشعريرة.
As I was saying, it's not typical!
كما كنت أقول، إنه ليس أمرا نموذجيا!
The count is indeed very good to us, but Mr. Rati is our master.
إن العد جيد جدًا بالنسبة لنا، لكن السيد راتي هو سيدنا.
I love my master.
أنا أحب سيدي.
What should I do, Kui?
ماذا يجب أن أفعل، كوي؟
You can do whatever you want.
يمكنك أن تفعل ما تريد.
Just not what you just did to me.
ليس فقط ما فعلته للتو معي.
I was just demonstrating. I would never smile at you like that.
كنتُ أُظهِر فقط. لن أبتسم لك هكذا أبدًا.
Get back to work!
العودة إلى العمل!
CIVIL SERVANTS SCHOOL
مدرسة الموظفين المدنيين
Bonjour. Mon nom est Theerathon.
مرحباً، اسمي ثيراثون.
Enchanté. Comment allez-vous?
يسعدني مقابلتك. كيف حالك؟
Bonjour. Je vais bien, et vous?
مرحباً، أنا بخير، وأنت؟
Je vais bien. Merci.
أنا بخير، شكرا لك.
Very good.
جيد جدًا.
How do you pronounce this word, and what does it mean?
كيف تنطق هذه الكلمة وماذا تعني؟
Does anyone know?
هل أحد يعرف؟
Maison.
بيت.
It means "house."
وهذا يعني "البيت".
Very good.
جيد جدًا.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Good luck on your examination.
أتمنى لك حظا سعيدا في امتحانك.
You can now begin.
يمكنك البدء الآن.
CIVIL SERVANTS SCHOOL
مدرسة الموظفين المدنيين
TEST
امتحان
Goodbye.
مع السلامة.
Thank you, Professor.
شكرا لك أستاذ.
No need to hurry. There's still time, sir.
لا داعي للاستعجال، لا يزال هناك وقت يا سيدي.
CIVIL SERVANTS SCHOOL
مدرسة الموظفين المدنيين
Professor!
أستاذ!
If I wanted to, how would I say, "Where would you like to go?"
لو أردت ذلك، كيف أقول، "إلى أين تريد أن تذهب؟"
Où veux-tu aller?
أين تريد أن تذهب؟
"Où veux-tu aller?"
"أين تريد أن تذهب؟"
Correct.
صحيح.
Où veux-tu aller?
أين تريد أن تذهب؟
"Where would you like to go?"
"أين تريد أن تذهب؟"
Là.
يكون.
Où veux-tu aller?
أين تريد أن تذهب؟
Je veux aller là-bas.
أريد أن أذهب إلى هناك.
Excellent.
ممتاز.
I'll be able to speak to French passengers now.
سأتمكن من التحدث مع الركاب الفرنسيين الآن.
Thank you, sir.
شكرا لك سيدي.
What's the matter, sir?
ما الأمر يا سيدي؟
Did I say something wrong?
هل قلت شيئا خاطئا؟
You speak as if we are not friends.
تتحدث وكأننا لسنا أصدقاء.
You don't think I'm your friend?
هل تعتقد أنني صديقك؟
We're at school.
نحن في المدرسة.
I think it will be improper if anyone hears us.
أعتقد أنه سيكون من غير اللائق أن يسمعنا أحد.
Mek.
يصنع.
Dech.
أنت.
Now that's more like it, Mek.
الآن هذا هو الأمر أكثر، ميك.
If anyone actually heard us,
إذا سمعنا أحد فعليا،
how would you even explain to them?
كيف يمكنك أن تشرح لهم ذلك؟
Try me.
جربني.
Who the hell do you think you are?
من تعتقد نفسك؟
How dare you speak so casually with my son?
كيف تجرؤ على التحدث بهذه الطريقة غير الرسمية مع ابني؟
Didn't you hear me?
ألم تسمعني؟
- Mek is my-- - Nothing but a simple commoner, sir.
- ميك هو-- - لا شيء سوى شخص بسيط يا سيدي.
I don't dare imagine myself on par with the baronet.
لا أجرؤ على تخيل نفسي على قدم المساواة مع البارونيت.
The baronet was so courteous to me, speaking with such civility.
لقد كان البارونيت لطيفًا جدًا معي، وتحدث معي بكل أدب.
I was only telling him to speak casually to make it appropriate, my lord.
كنت فقط أطلب منه أن يتحدث بشكل غير رسمي حتى يكون الأمر مناسبًا، يا سيدي.
He's right.
إنه على حق.
You misheard, Father. I was talking just now.
لقد أخطأت الفهم يا أبي. كنت أتحدث للتو.
Is that so?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Yes.
نعم.
A servant who knows his place is a servant I like.
الخادم الذي يعرف مكانه هو الخادم الذي يعجبني.
If you ever need work,
إذا كنت بحاجة إلى عمل في أي وقت،
come to my place.
تعال إلى مكاني.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
I think they've all gone to bed, my lord.
أعتقد أنهم جميعا ذهبوا إلى السرير، يا سيدي.
Should I try calling them?
هل يجب أن أحاول الاتصال بهم؟
No need.
لا حاجة.
That's all I came for. We're going home.
هذا كل ما جئت من أجله. سنعود إلى المنزل.
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي.
Did you come all the way here just to take a look at his rooftop?
هل أتيت إلى هنا كل هذه المسافة فقط لإلقاء نظرة على سطح منزله؟
- Is there a problem? - Of course not, sir.
- هل هناك مشكلة؟ - بالطبع لا سيدي.
We can stay all night if you want.
يمكننا البقاء طوال الليل إذا كنت تريد ذلك.
Let's go, then.
دعنا نذهب إذن.
Please, sir.
من فضلك سيدي.
Thee.
أنت.
Are you going to leave without even saying hello?
هل ستغادر دون أن تقول حتى مرحبا؟
You should have gone straight home after getting off work so late.
كان ينبغي عليك أن تذهب إلى المنزل مباشرة بعد الانتهاء من العمل في وقت متأخر.
I wanted to come here.
أردت أن آتي إلى هنا.
But?
لكن؟
I'd have been satisfied just seeing your bedroom window.
كنت سأكون راضيا فقط برؤية نافذة غرفة نومك.
That's my kind of rest.
هذا هو نوع الراحة المفضل لدي.
Thee.
أنت.
It's late.
إنه متأخر.
It would be inappropriate if anyone saw us.
سيكون من غير اللائق أن يراني أي شخص.
We're not doing anything inappropriate, are we?
نحن لا نفعل أي شيء غير لائق، أليس كذلك؟
Would you prefer it if we were?
هل تفضل أن نكون كذلك؟
Thee.
أنت.
You were waiting for me, weren't you?
لقد كنت تنتظرني، أليس كذلك؟
Otherwise, you would have gone to bed.
وإلا لكنت ذهبت إلى السرير.
No, I wasn't.
لا، لم أكن كذلك.
You really are unbending.
أنت حقا غير قابل للانحناء.
The Floating Lantern Festival is approaching.
يقترب مهرجان الفوانيس العائمة .
This coming full moon,
هذا القمر المكتمل القادم،
will you go to the Floating Lantern Festival with me?
هل ستذهب معي إلى مهرجان الفوانيس العائمة؟
What is a floating lantern?
ما هو الفانوس العائم؟
I won't tell you just yet.
لن أخبرك بعد.
I'll tell you that the event is fun and lively, though.
سأخبرك أن الحدث ممتع وحيوي، رغم ذلك.
It is?
إنها؟
Give me an answer first.
أعطني الجواب أولاً.
You promise to take me with you?
هل وعدتني أن تأخذني معك؟
Aren't you always enthusiastic when it comes to having fun?
ألا تشعر دائمًا بالحماس عندما يتعلق الأمر بالاستمتاع؟
Go to bed.
اذهب إلى الفراش.
It's late.
إنه متأخر.
You too.
أنت أيضاً.
Goodnight.
طاب مساؤك.
Go home.
اذهب إلى المنزل.
Go to bed.
اذهب إلى الفراش.
The Floating Lantern Festival takes place during the 12th month
يقام مهرجان الفوانيس العائمة خلال الشهر الثاني عشر
when the moon is at its fullest and brightest
عندما يكون القمر في أتم اكتماله وألمعه
and the tides touch the shores.
والمد والجزر يلامس الشواطئ.
We make krathong to float them in the river, don't we?
نحن نصنع الكراتونغ لتطفو في النهر، أليس كذلك؟
Yes.
نعم.
You're very good at cleaning banana leaves.
أنت جيد جدًا في تنظيف أوراق الموز.
You praise me too much, Thee.
لقد مدحتني كثيرًا، يا ثي.
It's not an impossible task, you know.
إنها ليست مهمة مستحيلة، كما تعلم.
I can't even praise you now?
لا أستطيع أن أثني عليك الآن؟
I wonder whose car that is.
أتساءل لمن هذه السيارة.
Mr. Rati.
السيد راتي.
Mr. Rati, sir.
السيد راتي، سيدي.
You have a visitor, sir.
لديك زائر يا سيدي.
Who is it, Kui?
من هو كوي؟
Hello, Rati.
مرحباً، راتي.
Florion!
فلوريان!
How did you get here?
كيف وصلت إلى هنا؟
By boat. I bring news from the French embassy and from your father.
بالقارب. أحضر أخبارًا من السفارة الفرنسية ومن والدك.
I still have trouble getting used to the boat trip to Siam.
لا أزال أواجه صعوبة في التعود على رحلة القارب إلى سيام.
I always end up throwing up from seasickness.
أنا دائما أتقيأ بسبب دوار البحر.
Mhay. Is your master all right?
مهى، هل سيدك بخير؟
It's the hot weather getting to him.
إنه الطقس الحار يؤثر عليه.
- Don't worry about him. - Sounds like they're having fun.
- لا تقلق بشأنه. - يبدو أنهم يستمتعون.
I have news from your father, Lutine.
عندي أخبار من والدك، لوتين.
He asked me to bring you news from France.
لقد طلب مني أن أحضر لك أخبارًا من فرنسا.
This is your father's message.
هذه رسالة والدك
What are they talking about?
ماذا يتحدثون عنه؟
It's only been a while since they last met.
لقد مر وقت طويل منذ آخر لقاء لهم.
Hardly long enough to have missed each other.
بالكاد كان هناك وقت كافٍ لكي نفتقد بعضنا البعض.
He even brought a letter?
حتى أنه أحضر رسالة؟
What's gotten into your master?
ماذا دخل سيدك؟
Look. He's talking to himself,
انظر. إنه يتحدث إلى نفسه،
and he's tearing those banana leaves to shreds.
وهو يمزق أوراق الموز إلى قطع صغيرة.
Whose master do you think is to blame?
من تعتقد أن سيده هو المسؤول؟
Do you know something I also suspect?
هل تعلم شيئا أشك فيه أيضا؟
I don't.
أنا لا.
I don't know how many lanterns we will make with this.
لا أعلم كم عدد الفوانيس التي سنصنعها بهذا.
- What are you all talking about? - Oh, it's…
- عن ماذا تتحدثون جميعًا؟ - أوه، إنه...
- This is difficult to cut, sir. - It is, my lord.
- من الصعب قطع هذا يا سيدي. - إنه كذلك يا سيدي.
We're helping each other out.
نحن نساعد بعضنا البعض.
This letter contains your return date to France.
تحتوي هذه الرسالة على تاريخ عودتك إلى فرنسا.
Good luck.
حظ سعيد.
Good luck to you too.
أتمنى لك حظا سعيدا أيضا.
Wow.
رائع.
It's beautiful.
إنه جميل.
You cannot go to the festival with anyone but me tonight.
لا يمكنك الذهاب إلى المهرجان مع أي شخص غيري الليلة.
As your guardian by duty,
باعتباري الوصي عليك بالواجب،
it is my sole responsibility to take you to the festival.
إنها مسؤوليتي وحدي أن آخذك إلى المهرجان.
You are abusing your power.
أنت تسيء استعمال سلطتك.
But I accept.
ولكنني أقبل.
I knew you'd be here.
لقد عرفت أنك ستكون هنا.
I was going to give you this book yesterday,
كنت سأعطيك هذا الكتاب بالأمس،
but Father got in the way.
ولكن الأب تدخل في الطريق.
Why didn't you tell my father yesterday that we are friends?
لماذا لم تخبر والدي بالأمس أننا أصدقاء؟
If I did, would your father have accepted it?
لو فعلت ذلك هل كان والدك سيقبله؟
You would at least be telling the truth.
على الأقل كنت تقول الحقيقة.
I didn't want to cause you any trouble.
لم أرد أن أسبب لك أي مشكلة.
Were you afraid my father would have you whipped?
هل كنت خائفة من أن والدي سوف يجلدك؟
I'm not afraid of getting hurt.
أنا لا أخاف من التعرض للأذى.
I appreciate the fact that you want to tell him we are friends.
أقدر حقيقة أنك تريد أن تقول له أننا أصدقاء.
Your feelings… aren't hurt?
مشاعرك... لم تتأذى؟
Are you worried about me?
هل أنت قلق علي؟
Hey, I'm being genuine.
مهلا، أنا أكون صادقا.
We are friends,
نحن أصدقاء
and I want to be a good one.
وأريد أن أكون جيدا.
Thanks, Dech.
شكرا لك، ديش.
I heard the Floating Lantern Festival tonight is going to be grand.
سمعت أن مهرجان الفوانيس العائمة الليلة سيكون رائعًا.
I take it you'll be in the ring fighting to win some money?
أعتقد أنك ستكون في الحلبة تقاتل من أجل الفوز ببعض المال؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
I do want to float a lantern like everyone else though.
أريد حقًا أن أطفو فانوسًا مثل أي شخص آخر.
Can you come?
هل يمكنك المجيء؟
My father insisted I must bring some lady whose name I don't even remember
أصر والدي على أن أحضر سيدة لا أتذكر اسمها حتى
to the festival tonight.
إلى المهرجان الليلة.
He forbids me to say no.
يمنعني من أن أقول لا.
That's good.
هذا جيد.
A festival is the perfect opportunity to go with a lover.
يعد المهرجان فرصة مثالية للذهاب مع الحبيب.
But I want to go with you.
ولكنني أريد أن أذهب معك.
I never listen to anyone anyway.
أنا لا أستمع إلى أحد على أي حال.
I'd rather go and have fun with a friend.
أفضّل أن أذهب وأستمتع بوقتي مع صديق.
But…
لكن…
See you.
أرك لاحقًا.
Mr. Rati.
السيد راتي.
I'm here to pick up my guardian.
أنا هنا لالتقاط الوصي الخاص بي.
I feel like a student just finishing school.
أشعر وكأنني طالب أنهى للتو دراسته.
I was afraid my guardian might think twice about taking me to the festival.
كنت خائفة من أن يفكر ولي أمري مرتين قبل أن يأخذني إلى المهرجان.
Thee.
أنت.
Hello.
مرحبًا.
This is Mom Rajawong Tikumporn Borrirak, the daughter of Duke Udomsawaddamrong,
هذه هي الأم راجاونج تيكومبورن بوريراك، ابنة الدوق أودومساوادامرونج،
the Minister of Education at the ministry where I work.
وزير التربية والتعليم في الوزارة التي أعمل بها.
Your grandmother asked me to accompany you back home for dinner
طلبت مني جدتك أن أرافقك إلى المنزل لتناول العشاء
before we go to the festival together.
قبل أن نذهب إلى المهرجان معًا.
Shall we?
هلا فعلنا؟
I'm afraid not.
لا للأسف.
I am…
أنا أكون…
Mr. Rati.
السيد راتي.
You have to go with the ministry's guest?
هل يتوجب عليك الذهاب مع ضيف الوزارة؟
It is entirely all right.
إنه على ما يرام تماما.
I will go with Jam and Kui. You should go, sir.
سأذهب مع جام وكوي. أنت يجب أن تذهب يا سيدي.
Mr. Rati.
السيد راتي.
I will go with you tonight, as promised.
سأذهب معك الليلة، كما وعدت.
You don't have to.
لا يجب عليك ذلك.
Wait for me.
الانتظار لي.
I will have Mhay tell you where to meet.
سأطلب من مهي أن يخبرك بمكان اللقاء.
At seven o'clock, I will hurry and join you there.
في الساعة السابعة، سأسرع وأنضم إليكم هناك.
You said your daughter speaks English well.
قلت أن ابنتك تتحدث الإنجليزية بشكل جيد.
Beautiful and talented, you'd be an asset to the work that Thee does.
جميلة وموهوبة، سوف تكونين إضافة قيّمة للعمل الذي تقومين به.
Don't you think, Thee?
ألا تعتقد ذلك يا ثي؟
I would never dare burden Lady Pa with my work like that.
لن أجرؤ أبدًا على إرهاق السيدة با بعملي مثل هذا.
"Lady Pa," Thee?
"سيدتي با" أنت؟
Don't be so distant.
لا تكن بعيدا جدا.
The Wisut and Borrirak families are long-time friends.
عائلتا ويسوت وبوريراك صديقتان منذ فترة طويلة.
You can speak casually with her.
يمكنك التحدث معها بشكل عادي.
I hope there is no problem with the betrothal we have spoken of.
أتمنى أن لا يكون هناك أي مشكلة في الخطوبة التي تحدثنا عنها.
I am, for one, in total support if my daughter has feelings for Mr. Thee.
أنا شخصياً أؤيد بشكل كامل إذا كانت ابنتي لديها مشاعر تجاه السيد ثي.
Well, you troublesome grandson?
حسنًا، هل أنت حفيد مزعج؟
I already have gifts prepared
لقد قمت بإعداد الهدايا بالفعل
to welcome my future granddaughter-in-law into the Wisut family.
للترحيب بحفيدتي المستقبلية في عائلة ويسوت.
- Mine is so much prettier than yours. - Only because you're better at making it.
- خاصتي أجمل بكثير من خاصتك. - فقط لأنك أفضل في صنعها.
- Of course I am. - Hello, Jam.
- بالطبع أنا كذلك. - مرحبًا، جام.
Hello.
مرحبًا.
Hey. Look at that.
مهلا، انظر إلى ذلك.
Appetizing!
شهية!
My mouth is watering.
فمي يسيل لعابه.
Mine too! Oh!
انا ايضا! اوه!
Look! Grilled chicken.
انظر! دجاج مشوي.
It's hot off the grill.
إنه ساخن من الشواية.
- Feel free to stop by. - Kui. Jam.
- لا تتردد في المرور. - كوي. جام.
It's almost nine o'clock.
إنها الساعة التاسعة تقريباً.
Let's go and wait for Thee at the gazebo by the river.
دعنا نذهب وننتظرك في شرفة الحديقة بجانب النهر.
I don't want him to wait.
لا أريده أن ينتظر.
- Yes, sir.
- نعم سيدي.
- I'll come back for the chicken. - And I'll come back for the cotton candy.
- سأعود من أجل الدجاج. - وسأعود من أجل غزل البنات.
I don't care.
لا أهتم.
Just make sure you share it with me.
فقط تأكد من مشاركتك معي.
Corn! Fresh corn!
ذرة! ذرة طازجة!
Dech.
أنت.
Dech, I want this.
ديتش، أريد هذا.
Fresh corn!
ذرة طازجة!
Is that all right?
هل هذا جيد؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
I want two of these.
أريد اثنين من هؤلاء.
And two of these, please.
واثنين من هؤلاء من فضلك.
Oh, grilled chicken!
أوه، دجاج مشوي!
Dech, look how good this is.
ديتش، انظر كم هذا جيد.
Is it all right if I buy this?
هل من المقبول أن أشتري هذا؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
It is always better to eat them cooked rather than raw.
من الأفضل دائمًا تناولها مطبوخة بدلاً من نيئة.
Thank you, Dech.
شكرا لك، ديش.
Hey, make it well done, like he said.
مهلا، قم بذلك بشكل جيد، كما قال.
I want two of these. And two of these.
أريد اثنين من هؤلاء. واثنين من هؤلاء.
- Take care of her. - Yes, sir.
- اعتني بها. - نعم سيدي.
It smells divine!
رائحتها إلهية!
Give me this one too.
أعطني هذا أيضاً.
And also this one.
وهذا أيضا.
Hold on, Dech--
انتظر يا ديتش--
- Where has he gone? - I don't know, ma'am.
- أين ذهب؟ - لا أعلم سيدتي.
Hey!
يا!
- Hey! - Sweet treats!
- مرحبا! - حلويات لذيذة!
Hey!
يا!
We have all kinds of sweet treats.
لدينا جميع أنواع الحلويات اللذيذة.
- Hey! - Treats!
- مرحبا! - يعامل!
Sweet treats!
حلويات لذيذة!
Hey! Hey!
مهلا! مهلا!
I want that. Oh!
أريد ذلك. أوه!
You want some sweet treats? Of course, dear.
هل تريدين بعض الحلويات؟ بالطبع يا عزيزتي.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
No…
لا…
My krathong!
كراتونغ الخاص بي!
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to do that.
أنا آسف. لم أقصد أن أفعل ذلك.
You should have held it more firmly.
كان ينبغي عليك أن تمسكها بقوة أكبر.
You couldn't even take care of a simple krathong.
لا يمكنك حتى الاهتمام بكراثونج بسيط.
How can you take care of me?
كيف يمكنك أن تعتني بي؟
My dear.
عزيزي.
My dear, wait for me!
عزيزي انتظرني!
You!
أنت!
Mek.
يصنع.
Run, sir.
أركض يا سيدي.
You all right?
هل انت بخير؟
I will have my son, Ram, look up the perfect date for the engagement.
سأطلب من ابني رام أن يبحث عن التاريخ المثالي للخطوبة.
Yes, ma'am.
نعم سيدتي.
Do it as soon as next week.
افعل ذلك في الأسبوع المقبل.
Yes.
نعم.
Marriage is not on my mind right now.
الزواج ليس في ذهني الآن.
All I want to focus on is serving my country.
كل ما أريد التركيز عليه هو خدمة بلدي.
You can still do that as a married man.
لا يزال بإمكانك القيام بذلك كرجل متزوج.
Am I right, Ram?
هل أنا على حق يا رام؟
Yes, Mother.
نعم أمي.
Lady Pa is still young.
السيدة با لا تزال شابة.
She is perfect in every way.
إنها مثالية في كل شيء.
I'd hate to see her suffer when I don't have time to care for her.
لا أريد أن أراها تعاني عندما لا أجد الوقت لرعايتها.
If I were to agree to this auspicious occasion,
لو وافقت على هذه المناسبة الميمونة،
I'm afraid it would do the lady more harm than good.
أخشى أن هذا قد يسبب للسيدة ضررًا أكثر من نفعه.
What a trivial concern.
يا له من قلق تافه!
I think it would be better to do it soon so people don't talk badly about you both.
أعتقد أنه سيكون من الأفضل القيام بذلك قريبًا حتى لا يتحدث الناس بشكل سيء عنكما.
Lady Pa is ready for marriage.
السيدة با جاهزة للزواج.
Am I right, dear?
هل أنا على حق يا عزيزتي؟
But I am not.
ولكنني لست كذلك.
If you're preoccupied with the matter with Monsieur Rati,
إذا كنت منشغلاً بالأمر مع السيد راتي،
I can transfer this duty to someone else.
أستطيع أن أنقل هذه المهمة إلى شخص آخر.
Taking care of Professor Rati is my responsibility.
رعاية البروفيسور راتي هي مسؤوليتي.
You promised Monsieur Lutine, the ambassador.
لقد وعدت السيد لوتين السفير.
That was mainly why he let his only son stay behind for this job.
وهذا هو السبب الرئيسي الذي جعله يسمح لابنه الوحيد بالبقاء خلفه للقيام بهذه المهمة.
To transfer this duty to someone else
لنقل هذا الواجب إلى شخص آخر
would be disrespectful to the ambassador.
سيكون هذا عدم احترام للسفير.
I feel it would be inappropriate.
أشعر أن هذا سيكون غير مناسب.
He's just a professor.
إنه مجرد أستاذ.
Professor Rati is staying for only a year.
سيبقى البروفيسور راتي لمدة عام واحد فقط.
I don't think anyone would object
لا أعتقد أن أحدا سوف يعترض
if this marriage were delayed for some months.
إذا تأخر هذا الزواج لعدة أشهر.
Come here.
تعال الى هنا.
Here.
هنا.
Careful.
كن حذرا.
How did you get yourself in trouble while taking a stroll with a lady?
كيف تعرضت للمشاكل أثناء نزهة مع سيدة؟
I didn't mean to get into it.
لم أقصد الدخول في هذا الموضوع.
I was going to pay him for it. You got in the way.
كنت سأدفع له ثمنها، لكنك أعاقتني.
Are you blaming me?
هل تلومني؟
I literally just saved you.
لقد أنقذتك للتو.
You were too hasty.
لقد كنت متسرعا جدا.
Yes. I was indeed hasty.
نعم لقد كنت متسرعاً بالفعل.
But I was only hasty because I was worried about you.
ولكنني كنت متسرعًا فقط لأنني كنت قلقًا عليك.
Hey!
يا!
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
We lost them.
لقد فقدناهم.
Come on.
تعال.
I'm glad you're talking to me like an actual friend.
أنا سعيد لأنك تتحدث معي كصديق حقيقي.
You should go back to your lady.
ينبغي عليك العودة إلى سيدتك.
She must be waiting for you.
لا بد أنها تنتظرك.
I told you.
أخبرتك.
I wanted to come here with you.
أردت أن آتي إلى هنا معك.
I don't want to stand by while she shops.
لا أريد أن أقف مكتوف الأيدي بينما تتسوق.
It's not fun.
إنه ليس ممتعا.
I'd rather be getting chased with you.
أفضّل أن أُطارَد معك.
I feel sorry for the lady now.
أنا أشعر بالأسف على السيدة الآن.
Don't you feel sorry for me?
ألا تشعر بالأسف تجاهي؟
I didn't want to come here with her.
لم أكن أريد أن آتي إلى هنا معها.
My father made me.
والدي صنعني.
He makes me do everything.
إنه يجعلني أفعل كل شيء.
He wants me to work at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
يريدني أن أعمل في وزارة الخارجية.
But since I'm not bright, he makes me study languages
ولكن بما أنني لست ذكيًا، فهو يجعلني أدرس اللغات
and introduces me to his powerful friends,
ويقدمني إلى أصدقائه الأقوياء،
hoping to secure me a shortcut.
على أمل تأمين لي طريق مختصر.
But it's obvious his friends' promises are empty.
ولكن من الواضح أن وعود أصدقائه فارغة.
No one wants to hire a slowpoke.
لا أحد يريد توظيف شخص بطيء.
That's why I secretly practice muay.
لهذا السبب أمارس رياضة الملاكمة سراً.
At least it's what I choose for myself.
على الأقل هذا ما اخترته لنفسي.
Muay is fun.
الملاكمة ممتعة.
It makes me feel like myself.
إنه يجعلني أشعر بأنني أنا.
I like doing muay.
أنا أحب ممارسة رياضة الملاكمة.
I've never told anyone any of that
لم أخبر أحدا بذلك مطلقا
except you.
إلا أنت.
I was deadly sick as a kid.
لقد كنت مريضًا للغاية عندما كنت طفلاً.
My mother worked hard to get me better.
لقد عملت والدتي بجد لكي تصبح أفضل.
She mortgaged the land that gave our family our livelihood,
لقد رهنت الأرض التي أعطت عائلتنا سبل العيش،
but we got cheated.
ولكننا تعرضنا للغش.
The interest was more than my mother could pay.
كانت الفائدة أكبر مما تستطيع والدتي دفعه.
And so she…
وهكذا هي...
She died of heartbreak.
لقد ماتت من الحزن.
That's when I started fighting.
وهنا بدأت القتال.
I'm doing everything I can to buy the land back.
أفعل كل ما بوسعي لشراء الأرض مرة أخرى.
I've also never told anyone that.
أنا أيضا لم أخبر أحدا بذلك من قبل.
This is what it is to be friends.
هذا هو ما يعنيه أن نكون أصدقاء.
Dech, my friend.
ديتش، صديقي.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
I have to get in the ring before everyone else takes my money.
يجب علي أن أدخل الحلبة قبل أن يأخذ أي شخص آخر أموالي.
I'll come with you.
سوف اتي معك
You'll have to catch up to me, then.
سيتعين عليك اللحاق بي إذن.
Mek!
يصنع!
- Ouch! - What?
- آخ! - ماذا؟
Kui, did you kick me?
كوي هل ركلتني؟
What?
ماذا؟
You fell down.
لقد سقطت.
I was just nodding off.
لقد كنت نائما فقط.
Mr. Rati, sir.
السيد راتي، سيدي.
The festival is going to end soon.
المهرجان سينتهي قريبا.
I believe it's nearly 11 o'clock.
أعتقد أن الساعة الآن تقترب من الحادية عشرة.
Shall we float the lanterns together?
هل نطفو الفوانيس معًا؟
She's right, sir.
إنها على حق يا سيدي.
I don't think he's coming. It's more likely he went with his fiancée.
لا أظن أنه سيأتي، على الأرجح أنه ذهب مع خطيبته.
- Kui! - Ow!
- اللعنة! - أوه!
What do you think you're saying?
ماذا تعتقد أنك تقول؟
Hmph!
همف!
Thee promised.
لقد وعدت.
He is coming.
إنه قادم.
Jam. Kui. You two should go ahead and float your lanterns.
جام. كوي. عليكما أن تُطفِئا فوانيسكما.
- Let's go. - Are you out of your mind?
- دعنا نذهب. - هل أنت خارج عقلك؟
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
It's late, sir.
لقد تأخر الوقت يا سيدي.
I don't want the deities going to bed before we pay our respects.
لا أريد أن تذهب الآلهة إلى النوم قبل أن نقدم احتراماتنا.
Hurry up.
اسرع.
Thee made this krathong from scratch.
لقد صنعت هذا الكراتونغ من الصفر.
How could he not come?
كيف لم يأتي؟
Right?
يمين؟
Would you like some krathong?
هل ترغب في بعض الكراتونغ؟
We also have water lilies.
لدينا أيضا زنابق الماء.
Hello there.
أهلاً بك.
Come on here for sweet treats.
تعالوا هنا لتناول الحلويات.
- Let's float some lanterns. - One baht each.
- دعونا نطفو بعض الفوانيس. - بات واحد لكل واحد.
Krathong over here.
كراثونغ هنا.
Buy your krathong here.
اشتري الكراتونغ الخاص بك هنا.
I'm aware talking about marriage makes you uncomfortable,
أنا أدرك أن الحديث عن الزواج يجعلك غير مرتاح،
but how can we disobey our parents?
ولكن كيف نستطيع أن نعصي والدينا؟
Sooner or later, it ought to happen.
عاجلا أم آجلا، ينبغي أن يحدث هذا.
This marriage is still a long way off.
لا يزال هذا الزواج بعيدًا جدًا.
I see no need to pay heed to it yet.
لا أرى ضرورة للاهتمام به بعد.
And you don't have to do that for me.
ولا يتوجب عليك أن تفعل ذلك من أجلي.
Take this krathong and float it as you should.
خذ هذا الكراتونغ وقم بتطفوه كما ينبغي.
You're not floating it with me?
أنت لا تطفو معي؟
I'll wait right here.
سأنتظر هنا.
My father and your grandmother meant for us to float this krathong together.
كان والدي وجدتك يقصدان أن نطفو على هذا الكراتونغ معًا.
Do you plan to float another krathong with someone else?
هل تخطط لتعويم الكراتونغ مرة أخرى مع شخص آخر؟
What would people say if they saw me float it by myself?
ماذا سيقول الناس إذا رأوني أطفو بمفردي؟
I will wait here.
سأنتظر هنا.
All right.
حسنًا.
If this is your refusal of me,
إذا كان هذا هو رفضك لي،
I hope you are prepared for the consequences.
أتمنى أن تكون مستعدًا للعواقب.
I am ready to face the consequences of the choices I made today.
أنا مستعد لمواجهة عواقب الاختيارات التي اتخذتها اليوم.
Please go.
من فضلك اذهب.
That person must be waiting.
لا بد أن هذا الشخص ينتظر.
I will close my eyes and count to three.
سأغلق عيني وأعد إلى ثلاثة.
When you are out of my sight, I'll take it that we lost each other in the crowd.
عندما تكون خارج مجال نظري، سأفترض أننا فقدنا بعضنا البعض في الحشد.
Please float your lantern.
من فضلك قم بتعويم فانوسك.
I'll wait here and walk you back to the car before I go.
سأنتظر هنا وأعود بك إلى السيارة قبل أن أذهب.
I want you to hurry up and leave.
أريدك أن تسرع وتغادر.
Don't stand here and make my humiliation of floating a lantern alone any worse.
لا تقف هنا وتجعل إهانتي في تحريك الفانوس بمفردي أسوأ.
One.
واحد.
Two.
اثنين.
Three.
ثلاثة.
Rati.
راتي.
Thee.
أنت.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Were you waiting long?
هل كنت تنتظر طويلاً؟
It's all right.
كل شيء على ما يرام.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
I want to try lighting fireworks.
أريد أن أحاول إشعال الألعاب النارية.
This is the last one.
هذا هو الأخير.
Would you like to share some snacks with me afterwards?
هل ترغب في مشاركة بعض الوجبات الخفيفة معي بعد ذلك؟
We haven't floated our lantern.
لم نطفو فانوسنا بعد.
We can do that later.
يمكننا أن نفعل ذلك لاحقًا.
Is there something on your mind?
هل هناك شيء في ذهنك؟
Will you talk to me?
هل ستتحدث معي؟
Is it something you can't tell me?
هل هذا شيء لا تستطيع أن تخبرني به؟
You really didn't float a lantern with anyone else?
هل حقا لم تطفو الفانوس مع أي شخص آخر؟
I didn't.
لم أكن.
What about that lady?
ماذا عن تلك السيدة؟
I don't want anything to do with Lady Pa,
لا أريد أن أفعل أي شيء مع السيدة با،
or any other ladies, for that matter.
أو أي سيدة أخرى، في هذا الشأن.
The only person I want to do anything with is you, Rati.
الشخص الوحيد الذي أريد أن أفعل أي شيء معه هو أنت، راتي.
But…
لكن…
What still bothers you? Just let me know.
ما الذي لا يزال يزعجك؟ أخبرني فقط.
You deserve to be happy with the right woman.
أنت تستحق أن تكون سعيدًا مع المرأة المناسبة.
One with whom you can have a traditional marriage.
الشخص الذي يمكنك الزواج منه بالطريقة التقليدية.
If "happy" is what you want me to be,
إذا كان "السعادة" هو ما تريدني أن أكون،
then I'm happy right now.
إذن أنا سعيد الآن.
What else is on your mind?
ماذا يجول في ذهنك أيضاً؟
Florion visited this morning
زار فلوريون هذا الصباح
to tell me when I'm going back to Paris.
ليخبرني عندما أعود إلى باريس.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
I knew from the beginning that you would go back to France one day.
لقد عرفت منذ البداية أنك ستعود إلى فرنسا يومًا ما.
But you're still the only person I want to float this lantern with, Rati.
لكنك لا تزال الشخص الوحيد الذي أرغب في أن يطفو هذا الفانوس معه، راتي.
Do you want to do that with me?
هل تريد أن تفعل ذلك معي؟
And your heart…
وقلبك…
How does it truly feel?
كيف تشعر حقا؟
Forget all rationality, and leave just your heart.
انسى كل العقلانية، واترك قلبك فقط.
Answer my question only with your heart.
أجب على سؤالي بقلبك فقط.
Do you have feelings for me…
هل لديك مشاعر تجاهي؟
the way I have feelings for you?
الطريقة التي أشعر بها تجاهك؟
I solemnly swear to the Goddess Ganga and all the deities here tonight
أقسم رسميًا للإلهة جانجا وجميع الآلهة هنا الليلة
that my body and my soul
أن جسدي وروحى
long only for Rati.
طويل فقط لراتي.
I solemnly swear to the Goddess Ganga
أقسم رسميًا للإلهة جانجا
and all the deities here tonight
وكل الآلهة هنا الليلة
that, from now on, my body and my soul
أنه من الآن فصاعدا، جسدي وروحى
will long for Thee,
سوف اشتاق إليك،
and only for Thee.
ولك فقط.
"Viscount Rati Jarupich"?
"الفيكونت راتي جاروبيتش"؟
Your title has been officially published in the Royal Gazette.
لقد تم نشر عنوانك رسميًا في الجريدة الملكية.
NEXT EPISODE
الحلقة القادمة
From now on, I believe things will only continue looking up for us.
من الآن فصاعدا، أعتقد أن الأمور سوف تستمر في التحسن بالنسبة لنا.
- Are you going to deliberately lose? - I…
- هل ستخسر عمدًا؟ - أنا...
- Mek! - Hey! Stop it!
- ميك! - هي! توقف!
I need to talk to you about the wedding between you and Lady Pa.
أريد أن أتحدث معك عن حفل الزفاف بينك وبين السيدة با.